Guide to the United Faculty and Pitt Professional Union Records, 1970-1995 AIS.1988.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Faculty and Pitt Professional Union Records
1970-1995
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Pitt Professional Union
University of Pittsburgh. United Faculty
AIS.1988.11
20 Linear Feet (16 boxes)
The United Faculty, a labor union affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers and American Association of University Professors, was formed in 1982 at the University of Pittsburgh out of the merger of the Pitt Professional Union and American Association of University Professors which both lost the right to represent the faculty in 1976. This collection contains bulletins and research information regarding the Pitt Professional Union's campaign to organize faculty at the University of Pittsburgh in 1976 and United Faculty's efforts in the 1980s and early 1990s.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Philip Wion, President of the United Faculty, in 1988.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
History
The United Faculty, an affiliate of the American Federation of Teachers and American Association of University Professors, formed in 1982 at the University of Pittsburgh out of the merger of the Pitt Professional Union and American Association of University Professors which both lost the right to represent the faculty in collective bargaining negotiations in 1976. Throughout 1984 and 1985, United Faculty and the university were locked in a legal battle over representation issues which resulted in a ruling that stated the union must represent all full-time and part-time faculty members with the exception of the medical school. In 1987, the union was forced to redirect its organization efforts when it was ruled that full-time professors are managers and, therefore, not eligible for collective bargaining. The union then put emphasis on part-time professors and librarians which were deemed to be eligible for union representation. A 1991 vote saw faculty and librarians at the university reject the United Faculty as a collective bargaining agent.
Related Material
Information files regarding the Pitt Professional Union and United Faculty exist within the University Archives.
American Federation of Teachers, Local 2067 Records, 1966-1980, AIS.1981.15, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh
American Federation of Teachers, Local 3412 Records, 1971-1980, AIS.1982.13, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains bulletins and research information regarding the Pitt Professional Union's campaign to organize faculty at the University of Pittsburgh in 1976 and United Faculty's efforts in the 1980s and early 1990s. Also included are membership lists and cards, meeting minutes, and information regarding a 1991 campaign that supported a state House of Representatives resolution that would grant public access to state university financial records.
Separated Material
Oversize materials are located in Range 1/12/2.
Previous Citation
United Faculty and Pitt Professional Union Records, 1970-1995, AIS.1988.11, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; College teachers' unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; University of Pittsburgh; Education; Labor; University of Pittsburgh -- Faculty; University of Pittsburgh. Pitt Professional Union; University of Pittsburgh. United Faculty; American Association of University Professors; American Federation of Teachers
- Administration Anti-Union Propaganda (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Association of University Professors (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Federation of Teachers Locals and Officer Directories (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Federation of Teachers Local 195 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- National American Federation of Teachers (Box 1, Folder 5)
- American Federation of Teachers and AFL-CIO Services (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Affirmative Action (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Allegheny County Labor Association (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bargaining Agents Breakdown (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Ina Braden (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Branch Campus Materials (Box 1, Folder 11)
- University Budget (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bulk Mailings (Box 1, Folder 13)
- PPU and AFT By-Laws and Constitutions (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous Materials (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Other American Federation of Teachers Pittsburgh Locals (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Pitt Professional Union Minutes, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Pitt Professional Union Newsletter, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
- Pennsylvania Federation of Teachers (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Support Personnel (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Telephone List (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Trades Council (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Temple University Union Information (Box 2, Folder 3-6)
- Organization (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Pennsylvania State Education Association-National Education Association (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Students (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Pennsylvania AFL-CIO News (Box 2, Folder 10)
- American Federation of Teachers Publications (Box 2, Folder 11)
- AFT In Action and On Campus (Box 2, Folder 12)
- American Teacher by AFT (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Changing Education, American Federation of Teachers (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous Materials (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Pittsburgh Federation of Teachers (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Pitt Update Bulletins (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Position Papers (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Douglas Radcliff-Umstead (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Representatives (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Questionnaire (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Sample Letters and Leaflets (Box 2, Folder 22)
- School of Education (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Senate, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Dr. William Smith (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Statistical File (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Election Ballots, September 1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Faculty and Staff Directory, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Volume 1)
- Justice vs. J.P. Stevens (Box 2, Volume 2)
- Agreement between the Board of Trustees of Junior College District No. 508, County of Cook and State of Illinois and Cook County College Teachers Union, Local 1600, AFT, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Volume 3)
- How to Beat Tenure Quotas: The Union Victory at City University, New York (Box 2, Volume 4)
- School Representatives Training Course Prepared by Vito DeLeonardis, Executive Director of New York State United Teachers, Inc. (Box 2, Volume 5)
- American Federation of Teachers Informational Packet (Box 2, Folder 28)
- AFT Advisory Commission on Higher Education (Box 3, Volume 1)
- Pitt Professional Union Statement of Postions, March 1976 (Box 3, Volume 2)
- Bargaining for Academic Democracy by Alfred Loewenthal and Robert Nielsen (Box 3, Volume 3)
- Either/Or? Both/And? Collective Bargaining and Academic Senates (Box 3, Volume 4)
- Miscellaneous Materials (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Collective Bargaining at Colleges (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Myths and Realities: A Department Chairperson Speaks Out by Pitt Professional Union (Box 3, Folder 4)
- University of Pittsburgh Review of the Fund Quarterly Period, March 31, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- The Conference of Faculty Unions in Public Higher Education (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Pitt Professional Union Bulletins (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Faculty Publicity and Position Papers (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Questionnaires (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Clippings (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Extra Election Ballots, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, Target Letters, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Draft Contract with Comments (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Part-Time Faculty Information (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Pitt Professional Union before Affiliation with AFT, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Lauffer Commission Reports (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Oskoui and Other Cases Against the University (Box 3, Folder 17)
- University Times (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Pitt News and Alumni News (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Tenure (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Materials (Box 4, Folder 4)
- American Federation of Teachers Pins (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Service Employees International Union District 1199P at Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- History of United Faculty, September 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Outline of the "Right to Know" Bill, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Publicity of the "Right to Know" Bill, October 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- "Right to Know" Materials and Information, October 1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- "Right to Know" Press Release to Senate Education Committee, October 18, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Sign Up Sheet for "Right to Know" Bill Petition, September 19, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Letters, "Prof Urges Support of 'Right to Know' Bill", October 10, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- "Right to Know" Petitions, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- House Bill No. 1075, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Background to the Petition "Right to Know", September 10, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- "Right to Know" Petition Advertisement (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Testimonies of Fiscal Accountabilities and "Right to Know" Bill, September 1991 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- "Cowell Bill Would Not Jeopardize Research" by Philip K. Wion, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Cowell Bill (Box 4, Folder 20)
- ULS News and Pennsylvania AAUP, September 1991 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Agreement between Wayne State University and the Wayne State University Chapter of the American Association of University Professors, July 1974-June 1976 (Box 5, Item 1-2)
- Amended Constitution of the Pennsylvania AFL-CIO, June 1983 (Box 5, Item 3)
- Collective Bargaining Agreement for Paraprofessionals between the Pittsburgh Board of Public Education and the Pittsburgh Federation of Teachers Local 400, December 1972-November 1975 (Box 5, Item 4-5)
- Agreement between the Board of Education of the School District of Philadelphia and the Philadelphia Federation of Teachers Local 3, September 1976-August 1978 (Box 5, Item 6)
- Agreement between the Board of Junior College District No. 542, County of Cook and State of Illinois and the Moraine Valley Faculty Association a Chapter of the Cook County College Teachers Union, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Item 7)
- Collective Bargaining Agreement between Association of Pennsylvania State College and University Faculties and Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, September 1974 (Box 5, Item 8)
- Collective Bargaining Agreement between Community College of Philadelphia and Faculty Federation of the Community College of Philadelphia Local 2026, September 1975-August 1980 (Box 5, Item 9)
- Working Draft of the Proposed Agreement between the Board of Regents and the United Faculty of Florida, 1976 (Box 5, Item 10)
- Pension Agreement between US Steel and United Steelworkers of America, 1976 (Box 5, Item 11)
- Program of Hospital and Physicians' Services Benefits for Eligible Pensioners, US Steel Agreement with United Steelworkers of America, 1975 (Box 5, Item 12)
- Program of Insurance Benefits, US Steel Agreement with United Steelworkers of America, 1975 (Box 5, Item 13)
- Supplemental Unemployment Benefit Plan, US Steel Agreement with United Steelworkers of America, 1974 (Box 5, Item 14)
- Savings and Vacation Plan, US Steel Agreement with United Steelworkers of America, 1973 (Box 5, Item 15)
- Steel Settlement by United Steelworkers of America, 1977 (Box 5, Item 16)
- ADE Bulletin of the Association of Departments of English, December 1973 (Box 5, Item 17)
- Faculty Voting Behavior in the Temple University Collective Bargaining Elections by Kenneth P. Mortimer and Naomi V. Ross, April 1975 (Box 5, Item 18)
- The Faculty Collective Bargaining Campaign at the University of Pittsburgh as Viewed Through the Campaign Literature by Jean Louis Rogers, April 1977 (Box 5, Item 19)
- American Federation of Teachers Constitution, July 1982 (Box 5, Item 20)
- Memorandum of Understanding between the Baord of Trustees of the Community College of Baltimore and the Community College of Baltimore Faculty Federation Local 1980, June 1972-June 1973 (Box 5, Item 21)
- Another College Collective Bargaining Contract, Philadelphia Community College, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Item 22)
- Agreement between Illinois Junior College District 525 and the Joliet Junior College Council of the Will County Federation of Teachers Local 604, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Item 23-24)
- Agreement between the Board of Trustees of Junior College District No. 508, County of Cook and State of Illinois and Cook County College Teachers Union, Local 1600, AFT, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Item 25)
- American Federation of Teachers Colleges and Universities Handbook (Box 5, Item 26)
- Standard Practice Instructions Binder (Box 5, Item 27)
- Correspondence and Bulletins (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
- Union Constitutional Amendements, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Pitt Professional Union Council Notes (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Member and Unsigned Faculty Cards (Box 6, Item 1)
- Other Teachers Union Agreements (Box 6, Item 2)
- Pitt Professional Union Scrapbook, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Item 3)
- Pitt Professional Union Fringe Benefits (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Pitt Professional Union Membership Meetings, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Pitt Professional Union American Federation of Teachers (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Pitt Professional Union Bulletin (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Pitt Professional Union Collective Bargaining (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Community College of Allegheny County AFT (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Pitt Professional Union Correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
- Pitt Professional Union Council Minutes, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Pitt Professional Union Council Executive Session, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Pitt Professional Union Council (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Pitt Professional Union Election Ballots, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Pitt Professional Union Election, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Pitt Professional Union Graduate Employees (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Nyden Grievance (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Pitt Professional Union General Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Pitt Professional Union Librarian Campaign (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Pitt Professional Union and the Pennsylvania Federation of Teachers (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Pitt Professional Union Position Papers, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Pitt Professional Union Resolutions (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Pitt Professional Union Council Minutes, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 20-21)
- Pitt Professional Union and Teachers for an Independent Faculty (Box 7, Folder 22)
- University of Pittsburgh Support Personnel Association (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Pitt Professional Union Working Papers (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, 1973-1980 (Box 7, Folder 25-32)
- University of Pittsburgh, Bradford Campus (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Campaigns (Box 7, Folder 34)
- School of Education, University of Pittsburgh (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Libraries (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Memoranda (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Pennsylvania State Education Association (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Position Papers and Statements (Box 7, Folder 40)
- University Senate (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Council Notes, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Nyden Grievance and Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 43-45)
- Flyers (Box 7, Folder 46)
- New York Teachers (Box 7, Folder 47)
- The Pennsylvania Professor (Box 7, Folder 48)
- The Pennsylvania Teacher (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Pittsburgh Federation (Box 7, Folder 50)
- University of Pittsburgh Telephone Directory, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Invoices (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Lease (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Pitt Professional Union Finances, 1977-1981 (Box 8)
- United Faculty Minutes, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Clippings and Member Cards (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
- Department Lists (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1983, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Meeting Minutes, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Correspondence and Minutes, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- The University Plan and Report of the Provost's Advisory Committee on Women's Concerns, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Officers' Report, Twenty-Third Constitutional Convention Pennsylvania AFL-CIO, April 27-30, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Proceedings of the 23rd Constitutional Convention, Pennsylvania AFL-CIO, April 27-30, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Meeting Minutes and Agenda, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Draft Statements, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- United Faculty Bulletins, 1984-1988 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Pennsylvania Labor Relations Board, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous Materials, 1984-1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- American Association of University Professors Membership Kit, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Membership Development: A Handbook for AAUP Recruiting (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Campaign to Organize Librarians (Box 9, Folder 19)
- United Faculty Posters (Box 9, Item 1)
- Hard Times, Values, and Academic Unions by Dr. Robert M. Nielson and Dr. Irwin H. Polishook (Box 9, Item 2)
- AAUP Policy Documents & Reports, 1984 (Box 9, Item 3-4)
- United Faculty Member Cards, 1985 (Box 10, Item 1)
- United Faculty Legislative Bulletin, October 3, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- CGS Student Government Letter Writing Workshop Announcement, October 6, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Senate Bill No. 1333, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Faculty Lists (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Service Employees International Union (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Faculty Cards (Box 11)
- Pennsylvania Labor Relations Board Hearings, 1975 (Box 12)
- Clippings (Box 13, Folder 1)
- PSEA Material (Box 13, Folder 2)
- AAUP Members by Department (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Statements and Letters to the Editor (Box 13, Folder 4)
- AAUP Temple University Material (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Pitt News and University Times Articles (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Dr. Seth Spaulding Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Campaign Plans (Box 13, Folder 8)
- AAUP Action (Box 13, Folder 9)
- AAUP/Pitt Newsletters (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Materials (Box 13, Folder 11)
- University of Pittsburgh Full Time Faculty, 1974 (Box 13, Item 1)
- Agreement between Temple University and the American Association of University Professors, Temple Chapter, 1973 (Box 13, Item 2)
- The Future of University Research by the Organization for Econmic Cooperation and Development, 1981 (Box 13, Item 3)
- Action Committee for Higher Education (Box 13, Item 4)
- AAUP Policy Documents and Reports, 1977 (Box 13, Item 5)
- AAUP Bulletin, December 1978 (Box 13, Item 6)
- Academe by the American Association of University Professors, March-June 1983 (Box 13, Item 7-8)
- Blank Member Cards (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Council Meetings, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- University Graduate Employees (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Pennsylvania Labor Relations Board Hearing, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- United Faculty Steering Committee (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Pitt Professional Union Council Minutes, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Pitt Professional Union Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Pitt Professional Union Yeshiva Case (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Pitt Professional Union, American Association of University Professors Pitt Chapter (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Pitt Professional Union Constitution (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Pitt Professional Union Contract (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Pitt Professional Union Legislation Research (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Pitt Professional Union Mailings (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Pitt Professional Union Newspaper Clippings (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Pitt Professional Union Work Study (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Pitt Professional Union and the Board of Trustees (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 13)
- American Association of University Professors and Pitt Professional Union Merger (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Budget (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Model Contract (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Council (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Insurance (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Membership Lists (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Organization (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Planning Documents (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Questionnaires (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Research Documents (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Employee Information (Box 14, Folder 24)
- National Labor Board Orders (Box 14, Folder 25)
- Pitt Professional Union Publicity (Box 14, Folder 26)
- Unfair Labor Practice Charges (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Women and the American Federation of Teachers (Box 14, Folder 28)
- Pitt Professional Union Literature (Box 14, Folder 29)
- Pitt Professional Union Press Releases (Box 14, Folder 30)
- Productivity (Box 14, Folder 31)
- Strike Information (Box 14, Folder 32)
- Department Representative and Union Member Lists (Box 14, Folder 33)
- The AFT Organizer (Box 14, Folder 34)
- Union (Box 14, Folder 35)
- Work Study Receipts (Box 14, Folder 36)
- Photographs (Box 14, Folder 37)
- Collective Bargaining Agreement between Hofstra University and the Hofstra Chapter of the American Association of University Professors, 1991-1996 (Box 14, Item 1)
- Agreement between the City University of New York and the Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York, 1984-1987 (Box 14, Item 2)
- Collective Bargaining Agreement between the University of Connecticut Board of Trustees and the University of Connecticut Chapter of the American Association of University Professors, 1984-1986 (Box 14, Item 3-4)
- Contract Development in Higher Education Faculty Collective Bargaining by Joel M. Douglas and Molly Garfin (Box 14, Item 5)
- Agreement between the Board of Trustees of the California State University and the California Faculty Association, 1987-1991 (Box 14, Item 6)
- Membership Development: A Handbook for AAUP Recruiting with Notes (Box 14, Item 7)
- Agreement between the University Teachers' Union University of Montana and the Montana University System, 1983-1987 (Box 14, Item 8)
- Collective Bargaining Agreement between the Community College of Philadelphia and the Faculty Federation of the Community College of Philadelphia, Local 2026 American Federation of Teachers, 1985-1990 (Box 14, Item 9-12)
- Agreement between Temple University and the American Association of University Professors/American Federation of Teachers, Local 4531, 1988-1990 (Box 14, Item 13)
- Agreement between Association of Pennsylvania State College and University Faculties and State System of Higher Education, 1990-1993 (Box 14, Item 14)
- Agreement between Wayne State University and the Wayne State University Chapter of the American Association of University Professors, 1990-1992 (Box 14, Item 15)
- Agreement between the State of New York and United University Professions, 1988-1991 (Box 14, Item 16)
- Agreement between Rutgers University and Rutgers Council of AAUP Chapters, 1989-1992 (Box 14, Item 17)
- A New Beginning for Pitt: The United Faculty's Platform for Collective Bargaining, 1991 (Box 14, Item 18)
- Pennsylvania Labor Relations Board Hearing Transcripts, 1975 (Box 15)
- United Faculty Binder, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- United Faculty, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Librarians List, February 6, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Council Minutes, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Cowell Petition, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- United Faculty (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Turner Case, December 1992 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
- United Faculty David Rosenberg (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Secretary Agenda, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- United Faculty Newsletter, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Letter to Peter F.M. Koehler, Dean, Faculty of Arts and Sciences, January 25, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- United Faculty Correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- United Faculty Minutes, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- United Faculty Member Lists, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Senate Budget Policies Committee, Salary Issues (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Hoke/Biancheria (Box 16, Folder 17)
- United Faculty Current Notes, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- United Faculty, Right to Know, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Petitions (Box 16, Folder 20)
- United Faculty Campaign Committee, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 21)
- United Faculty, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 22)
- United Faculty Research (Box 16, Folder 23)
- United Faculty Membership Materials (Box 16, Folder 24)
- United Faculty Contracts (Box 16, Folder 25)
- New Faculty Campaign (Box 16, Folder 26)
- AFT and AAUP (Box 16, Folder 27)
- United Faculty, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 28-30)
- United Faculty Campaign, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 31-33)